<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PWC Dept Repository</string>
    <string name="select">Select Language</string>

    <string name="arts1">
        • Film and Music appreciation and creative writing classes. \n\n
        • Exposure visit to various Media Houses. \n\n
        • Creative Bulletin Board assignments. \n\n
        • Annual Media Workshop, Exhibition, Quiz. \n\n
        • Annual Study tour to media-related organizations. \n\n
        • Hands-on training in photography, video production and radio production. \n\n
        • Theater Workshop – Drama \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="arts1faculties">
    • Dr. Tauseef Hassan (HoD)\n
      M.A., MJMC, B.Ed\n
      Advertising and Communication Management\n\n

    • Mr. Amitabh Ranjan\n
      MA ,UGC NET\n
      Print,TV and Radio\n\n

    • Dr. Dharmendra Kumar Singh\n
      MBA, NET (UGC),Ph.D\n\n

    • Ms. Runa\n
      M.A. in English\n\n

    • MR. Prashant Ravi\n
      Export management, Digital Journalism\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="arts2">
        • The Department of English was established in 1940. \n\n
        • The department aims at creating a learning environment
        that is conducive to the development of critical faculty
        – the ability to think critically and independently – and
        making of socially responsible and committed students
        who have imbibed human values and are ethical in their
        practices.\n\n
        • The department focuses not only on imparting curriculum
        based theoretical knowledge but also on sensitising students
        towards important issues and subjects, so that the acquired
        learning can translate into positive social intervention.\n\n
        • The activities of the department aim at providing learning
        opportunities and exposure to the students. The regular activities
        include poetry writing and recitation, Skit based on literary texts,
        research project and poster making. Apart from this the department
        holds varied activities to promote student participation and performance.\n\n
        • Guest lectures, seminars, interactive sessions on relevant themes are also organised.\n\n
        • Movies / documentaries are screened and film appreciation classes organised.\n\n
        • Teachers of the Department provide constant guidance – both academic and personal – to
        the students. Each teacher acts as a mentor to a group of students. Students share their
        academic and personal problems and the mentor provides counselling to the students.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="arts2faculties">
          • Dr. Sahar Rahman (HOD)\n
            M.A, Ph.D\n
            Postcolonial Fiction\n\n

           • Dr. Shahla Rehana\n
             M.A, Ph.D\n
             Asian English\n\n

           • Dr. Richa\n
            M.A (English), NET, Ph.D\n
            Sexuality, Gender and Ecology\n\n

           • Ms. Nikhila Narayanan \n
             M.A (English), NET, B.Ed \n
             Ecology and Literature \n\n

           • Sr. M. Nelsa A.C. \n
             M.A (English)\n
             Postcolonial Literature \n\n

           • Dr. Devina Krishna \n
             M.A (Linguistics), NET, M.Phil and Ph.D \n\n

           • Dr. Deepika Tiwari \n
             MA(English), NET, Ph.D \n\n

           • Dr. Apurba Paul \n
             M.A (English), NET, Ph.d \n\n

            • Dr. Prabhat Jha \n
              PhD, NET \n\n

           • Muniba Sami\n
             PhD, NET \n\n
       </string>


    <string name="arts3">
             • The Department of Economics has maintained a high standard
            in the personality development of students \n\n
            • The department aims at the holistic development of its students \n\n
             • Apart from the conventional course, the Department has launched a UGC recognized and sponsored
            Add-on career-oriented course on ‘Public Relations’ at three levels-Certificate, Diploma, and Advanced Diploma.\n\n
             • Mostly our students are university toppers and rank holders. \n\n
             • Students excel in various MBA Courses and are selected for the same. \n\n
             • There has been an excellent performance in national level competitions. \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts3faculties">
            •  Dr. Zareen Fatima(HOD) \n
               M.A., B.Ed, Ph.D \n
               Monetary Economics \n\n

            •  Ms. Kamaljeet Kaur \n
               M.A Economics, UGC NET \n\n

            •  Ms. Vijeta lal \n
               M.A Economics,UGC NET, B.Ed \n\n

            •  Dr. Maryam Sabreen \n
               M. Phil ,MA, NET \n\n

             • Ms. Priti Kumari \n
               M.A, U.G.C – NET and JRF\n
               Econometrics \n\n

             • Dr. SWASTIKA SATYAM \n
               M.A Ph.D. \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts4">
                 • Organising Fashion displays. \n\n
                 • Participating in Mahila Udyog Mela every Year Since 1997, Patna.\n\n
                 • Visit to garment manufacturing units, export houses and designing institutes in India.\n\n
                 • Visit to different traditional craft centers of India.\n\n
                 • Organizing art and craft competitions.\n\n
                 • Workshops and guest lectures.\n\n
                 • Students go for the job training every year.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts4faculties">
             • Dr Shemushi Ityalam Madhu(HOD) \n
                M.A, PGDFD, Ph.D \n
                Apparel Craft \n\n

             • Ms. Asha Pandey \n
                PGDFD,BFA(Fine Arts) \n
                Basic Design \n\n


             • Ms. Geetanjali Choudhary \n
                PGDFD,M.A., MFA \n
                CAD \n\n

             • Ms. Priyanka Singh \n
                PGDFD, B.Ed.,M.A \n
                Illustration \n\n

             • Ms. Vandana Sinha \n
                PGDCA,PGDFD,FCT \n
                Clothing Technology \n\n

             • Ms. Purnima Roy \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts5">
         • The Department imparts P.G. and UG of Geography based on CBCS syllabus.\n\n
         • The students of the department excel in University Examination every year with 100% result and top ranks. \n\n
         • Teaching-learning process is up to date in the department with regular use of Smartboards, ICT aids, and other teaching aids.\n\n
         • The Department has a well-furnished laboratory and a departmental library. \n\n
         • On regular basis the students participate in various co-curricular and extra-curricular
            activities such as seminar, quiz, poster making, debate, power point presentation, exhibition, study tour etc. \n\n
         • Final year students take up research projects every year on relevant socio-economic issues. \n\n
         • National Seminars and Workshops are organized on regular basis on contemporary themes. \n\n
         • Department runs a Credit base Add- On Certificate course on ‘Travel and Tourism Management’. \n\n
         • The teachers of the department have undertaken ‘Research Project’ and they keep themselves updated by
            attending National/ International Seminars and publishing research articles in reputed journals. \n\n
         • The Department has undertaken an outreach programme ‘Manthan’ under which the students of the department, accompanied
            by a faculty member provide remedial coaching to the under-privileged school students at ‘Manthan’  NGO, Khagaul every Saturday. \n\n
         • The alumni of the department are well placed in various capacities such as Civil Services, lectureship, banking, and corporate sector.
            Some of the well-placed alumni are: Madhu Malti Ghosh, IAS, Ms. Nilima  Kumari , IAS, Ms. Sheela Irani, Bihar Police Service, Ms. Divya,
            IAS, Prof. Ravi Kiran Sharma, Prof. in Geography, P.U., Ms. Swarnim Sinha, Urban Planner, California, Vihag Guru, Vice President, Yes Bank Ltd. \n\n
            </string>

    <string name="arts5faculties">
            •  Dr. Amrita Chowdhury (HOD)\n
               M.A, Ph.D \n\n

            •  Sister Anna A.C\n
               M.A. Gold medalist \n
               Urban, Political and Population Geography \n\n

             • AISHWARYA RAJ \n
               UGC-NET, M.A., B.Ed \n\n

             • Meenakshi Mishra \n
               UGC-NET, M.Tech, M.A. \n\n


            •  Tulika Kumari \n
               M.A. UGC-NET. \n\n

            •  Dr.Awadhesh Kumar \n
               UGC-NET, M.Tech, M.A \n\n

            • DR. ARVIND KUMAR \n
                NET/JRF, M.A., Ph.D.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts6">

            • Department has maximum number of students as AECCHINDI is a compulsory subject with English.\n\n
            • Every year Hindi Pakhwada is organized to mark Hindi Diwas.\n\n
            • The faculty members are constantly engaged in Research work by presenting papers, publishing articles and guiding CPE Projects. \n\n
            • Most of the students are well placed in Government and Private sectors. \n\n
            • Many students are working as teachers, Principals and Professors in schools and Universities.\n\n
            • Every year a few students clear NET and JRF. \n\n
            • Proof reading, Translation and Script writing is also done by faculty members on regular basis. \n\n
            • Cultural and Educational Activities, Mentor system and Parent-Teacher MEET are some healthy practices of the Department. \n\n

        <!--    Our Alumni \n\n-->

        <!--            1. Prof.Mangala Rani,Department of Hindi,College of Commerce, Patna, PPU \n-->
        <!--            2. Dr. Vibha Kumari,Head, Department of Hindi, Patna College, P.U. \n-->
        <!--            3. Sister Soni,Principal, Carmel School, Gorakhpur,U.P. \n-->
        <!--            4 . Devashree,Assistant Commissioner of State Taxes,Commercial Tax Department, Bihar \n-->
        <!--            5.  Nandini,Pre School Teacher,Safari Kids,California, U.S.A\n-->
        <!--            6. Indra Singh,Rajbhasha Adhikari,Bank of India \n-->
        <!--            7 . Parinita,Rajbhasha Adhikari,Union Bank \n-->

        </string>

    <string name="arts6faculties">
             • Dr. Manjula Sushila \n
            HOD,M.A, Ph.D \n
            Upanyas \n\n

             • Dr. Deepa Srivastava \n
            M.A, Ph.D, NET,MJMC \n
            Gadya Sahitya \n\n

             • Dr. Sushma Choubey \n
            M.A, Ph.D \n
            Upanyas \n\n


             • Dr. Brahma Nand \n
            M.Phil, Ph.D \n\n

             • Dr. Kumar Dhananjay \n
            M.Phil, Ph.D \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts7">
             •We aim to make the student’s worthy citizens and better human beings
            by letting them acquire deeper knowledge of the past, energetic living of the present and looking forward to sustainable hope. \n\n
             •Seminars, Projects, Quiz Programmes, field trips, educational trips, cultural activities, personality classes with films. \n\n
             •Regular terminal examinations, as well as weekly class examinations. \n\n
             •Counseling, conducting prayer, celebration of special festivals, National Days etc. \n\n
             •CPE Minor Projects, class projects on various topics like empowerment of women and other Social issues. \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts7faculties">

            •Sister Celine Cresta,A.C.(HOD) \n
            M.A. Ph.D \n
            Medieval India \n\n

            •Ms. Shreya Singh \n
            M.A, NET \n\n

           • Dr. Priyanka \n
            PhD \n\n

            •Ms. Bhawana Singh \n
            M.A., NET JRF \n\n

            •Dr. RANJU KUMARI \n
            M.A., PhD \n\n

            •DR. ASHA SHARMA \n
            PhD \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts8">
             •The Department of Home Science provides need-based education to girl students in the
            theory and practice to meet the day to day challenges of life. This would enable them to play
            diverse roles in life as a housewife, a working woman, a mother, a nation builder and a responsible and responsive human being. \n\n
             •Over the years our P.G students have won laurels and were the recipients of Gold Medals in the University examinations. \n\n
             •Research work is undertaken by the students at P.G and U.G levels under the supervision and guidance of the department staff. \n\n
             •A Health Centre was inaugurated in the year 2010. Health check-ups for the college staff and students are conducted periodically. \n\n
             •Department holds various Awareness Programmes /Interactive Sessions /Seminars for the staff and students on various health issues, first
            aid, disaster management and so on and many eminent doctors are invited to give input sessions. \n\n
             •National and International Days of importance-National Nutrition Week, First Aid  Day, Dietetic Day and so on, are
            marked with various programmes like quiz, exhibition, poster competition etc. \n\n
             •Teachers upgrade themselves by attending refresher courses /national -international seminars/symposium. They also
            present papers and publish an article in journals.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts8faculties">

             •Dr. Sister Maria Tanisha, A.C. (HOD) M.A PhD \n
            Composite \n\n

            • Dr. Shazia Husain \n
            Ph.D., UGC NET-JRF, M.Sc.\n\n

            • Dr. Nisha Kumari \n
            M.A, B.Ed, NET, Ph.D. \n\n

             •Dr. Suniti Bhagat \n
            M.Sc. , Ph.D., NET\n
            Textile \n\n

             •Dr. Rosy Kumari \n
            Ph.D, M.Sc. \n\n

        </string>

    <string name="arts9">
             • The Department is equipped with an air-conditioned state-of-the-art computer lab. \n\n
             • Mass Communication, Reporting and Editing, Audio Visual Media, Design and Graphics, Photojournalism,
            Public Relation, and Advertising etc. form a part of the syllabus. \n\n
            •  On the Job training in the Print Media for the 1st year students and in Electronic
            Media/ PR/ Advertising agencies for the 2nd year students during May-June is a compulsory part of the curriculum. \n\n
             • During the 3rd year, the students are taken a study tour to places like Mumbai, Goa, Hyderabad, Chandigarh, and
            Amritsar where they visit various organizations of the Print Media and Electronic Media apart from the local sightseeing
              The students take part in Seminars, Workshops, Co-curricular activities. \n\n
             • The BMC library has a rich collection of books, magazines, and daily newspapers and in addition an LCD TV with a
            Projector and screen and a laptop to facilitate exposure of the electronic media. \n\n
             • The USP of the department is its lab journal ‘Headway’ which gives exposure to the students of BMC to learn the finer
            nuances of Print Journalism while I-Mac with FCP (Final Cut Pro ) gives them hands-on training in Video Production. Throughout the
            year the students are busy shooting, recording, editing, writing scripts and other media related work under the guidance of experts from respective fields. \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts9faculties">

             • Ms. ROMA(HOD) \n
            Phd ( Pursuing) ,UGC NET \n\n

             • Ajay Kumar Jha \n
            M.A. MJMC, Political Science \n\n

             • Ms. Divya Gautam \n
            Phd(Pursuing), UGC-NET \n\n

             • Ms. Ankita \n
            UGC NET, Pursuing PhD \n\n

             • Mr. Prasant Ravi \n
            Diploma in Photography, Photo Journalism \n\n

             • Mr. Gaurav Aranya \n
            MJMC,UGC NET \n\n

             • Ms. Aprajita Pathak \n
            UGC-NET \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts10">
            •  The faculty members are constantly engaged in extension services, presenting papers, publishing articles, projects, and authoring books. \n\n
            • One of the students of this department is now a judge of Jaipur High Court (Justice Gyan Sudha Mishra)\n\n
            • Department organizes Seminar, Conference and Symposium on a regular basis on current issues like Human Rights, Women’s Studies, Environment etc.\n\n
            •  Department runs two add-on courses in Human Rights and Value education and Women’s Studies. \n\n
            •  The Department of Political Science is one of the star departments of the College.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts10faculties">
            •  Dr. Vinita Priyedarshi \n
                M.A, Ph.D \n
                Expert in Political theory and International Relations \n\n


            • Ms. Fiza Darakshan \n
                M.A, NET, pursuing PhD\n
                Expert in Indian Constitution Public Administration \n\n

            •  Mr. Adweetiya Sinha \n
                MA,NET, Pursuing PhD. \n\n

            • Ms. Simran Sinha \n
                MA, NET\n\n

            •   Ms. Jyoti Rani \n
                MA, NET \n\n

            • Ms. Taniya Banerjee \n
                MA, NET \n\n
        </string>


    <string name="arts11">
               •  Research projects are being carried out successfully due to the sufficient availability of psychological tests.\n\n
                • Educational tour for B.A. III students to mental hospitals is conducted.\n\n
               •  A full-time counselor is available in the guidance and counseling center.\n\n
               •  Psychiatrists/Counselors are invited to the Dept. for lectures and interactions.\n\n
                • Students from all Departments of Patna Women’s College come for guidance and counseling. They are counseled to face their day-day problems.\n\n
               •  Regular talks are conducted related to psychological issues by internal and external resource persons.\n\n
                 •Through the Mentor System, the Department offers help and guidance for personal and educational problems of students.\n\n
                • Seminars and Workshops are held at regular intervals.\n\n
                 •Parent-Teacher Meet are held regularly to help in personality development.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts11faculties">

                • Ms. Nupur Sinha(HOD) \n
                M.A., Ph.D \n\n

                • Ms. Mukta Mrinalini \n
                M.A., UGC-NET, M.Phil, PhD \n\n

                • Dr. Medha \n
                M.A, Ph.D \n\n

                 •Dr. Sr. M. Reema A.C.\n
                M.A, Ph.D \n
                Clinical Psychology, Counselling \n\n

               •  Ms. Aradhana kumari \n
                M.A,UGC- NET (PURSUING Ph.D ) \n\n

                • Ms. Nupur Shree \n
                M.A, UGC NET \n\n

                • Ms. Manisha Kumari \n
                M.Phil, Diploma \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts12">
                 • The Department conducts Certificate, Diploma and Advanced Diploma Add-on Courses in Applied Yoga.\n\n
                 • The Department organized a UGC Sponsored National Seminar on Social, Ethical and Legal Issues Related to Euthanasia and se
            veral workshops and webinars on YOGA.\n\n
                 • Departmental activities like seminar quiz, speech contest, poster competition are held on a monthly basis.\n\n
                 • Three teachers of the department have been awarded Minor Research Projects by the UGC, which they have successfully submitted. \n\n
                • The Department celebrates inmortant days like Swami Vivekananda Jayanti, Buddha Jayanti,International day of YOGA World Philosophy Day every year.\n\n
                • Philosophy is a student-friendly subject especially because of its syllabus.\n\n
                 • It is a scoring subject for Civil Services Examinations. \n\n
                • For the main exam of UPSC and the different States Public Service Commission, there is one compulsory paper of 300 marks on Ethics, Integrity, and
            Aptitude. Ethics is an important branch of Philosophy.\n\n
               • Logical reasoning is also an important part of competitive exams which is taught in Philosophy.\n\n
                • Philosophy teaches values which is necessary for the upliftment of the society.\n\n
                • Indian philosophy has its roots in the Vedas and the Upanishads by studying which the student will become acquainted with the culture of India.\n\n
                • Contemporary Philosophy critical studies the social and political problems thereby providing the right direction to them.\n\n
                • In all the IITs and NITs there is a Humanities Department. Philosophy is a subject to be studied there.\n\n
               •  In the IIMS there is a compulsory paper on Value Studies and Ethics.\n\n
                • In B. Ed. as well as in Teacher’s Training Classes Educational Philosophy is taught as an important paper.\n\n
                 • Philosophy is a good subject for higher studies and research.\n\n
                • Teachers of the department regularly publish articles in newspapers, journals, Magazines. Some have even published books.\n\n
                • Guest lectures on “Ethics and Values” or “Importance of Philosophy in Life” are also held in the department. \n\n
                • Parent-Teacher meet is also regularly held in the department. \n\n
                • Students of the department regularly engage themselves in CPE Research Projects on important social and political issues from philosophical perspective.\n\n
                • Students of the department are among the ten top rank holders in the University. \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts12faculties">
               •  Dr. Ameeta Jaiswal(HOD) \n
                M.A, Ph.D \n
                Ethics \n\n

                • Dr. Kumkum Rani \n
                M. A, Ph.D \n
                Religion \n\n

                • Dr. Keerti Chaudhary \n
                M.A, Ph.D NET/JRF \n\n

               •  Dr. Kamlendra Kumar \n
                Ph.D, NET, JET (JPSC), B.Ed, M.Ed \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts13">

             •The Department of Social Work has been recently introduced in the year 2020 in Patna Women’s college as sociology being the parent department. \n\n
             •The Department has started functioning with its first batch (2020-2022, Ist Semester) with a total of seventeen students and two faculty members. \n\n
            • Currently, the Department is offering postgraduate degree (M.A. in Social Work) \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts13faculties">

            • Dr. Mridul Mishra (HOD) \n
            MSW (BHU Gold Medal), \n
            Ph.D.(NET,JRF)\n\n

            • Dr. Chandni Sinha \n
            M.A., Ph.D \n
            Industrial Sociology \n\n

            • Ms. Sister Sanjana A.C.\n
            Community Development (CD), MSW \n\n

            • Ms. Akanksha \n
            MSW, UGC NET  \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts14">
     • Department of Sociology was established in the year 1987. The Department offers Undergraduate Programme. \n\n
    • The Department consists of highly qualified and experienced faculty. It also has rich Departmental Library.\n\n
    • It is a Parent Department of Master’s in social work (MSW) programme since 2020.\n\n
    • The faculty members of the department are constantly engaged in Research Work through paper presentations, papers and articles publications
    and supervising students with CPE projects and Dissertations.\n\n
    • The Department seeks to develop in students the sociological knowledge and skills that will enable them to think critically
            and imaginatively about society and social issues.\n\n
    • The faculty members help their students to prepare themselves for careers in teaching, delivery and administration of
            social and health services, urban and environmental studies, Law and Government services.\n\n
    • Department conducts various Cultural and Academic related activities like Debates, Extempore, Quiz, Poster making and essay writing with the aim to
    provide exposure to the students and help them develop their overall personality. Apart from this, students are encouraged to participate in programs
            at college, university and national level.\n\n
    • Guest lectures, webinars, exchanges programs, value judgement classes and interactive sessions on relevant themes are also organized.\n\n
    • Constant guidance and counselling is provided to the students by the teachers through process of Mentoring.\n\n
    • Parent-Teacher Meet is also conducted by the department to discuss and assess the progress of the students with the parents.\n\n
    Student Profile \n\n
    • Department has approximately 250 students in core course currently.\n\n
    • Most of our students are toppers and university rank holders and have cleared competitive examinations like UGC NET-JRF, GATE. \n\n
    • Many of are students are working as professors in universities, teacher in government or private schools, officers in banks, working with law firms and
    NGO’s and qualified civil services examinations.\n\n
        <!--    ALUMNI-->
        <!--    • Devopriya Dutta, Environmentalist & UN Youth Coordinator at Tarumitra. \n-->
        <!--    • Mrinal Manjari, Assistant Professor (Bpsc) at J. D. Women’s College, Patliputra University.  \n-->
        <!--    • Naina Jha, Creative Director at Instinct, Social Worker. \n-->
        <!--    • Soumya Saloni, works with National University of Educational Planning and Administration. \n-->
        <!--    • Anubha Sinha, Legal Analyst. \n\n-->
        </string>

    <string name="arts14faculties">
                 •Dr. Tapashi Bhattacharjee(HOD) \n
                M.A., B.Ed, Ph.D Anthropology \n\n

                 •Ms. Samiksha  \n
                M.A, B.Ed, Ph.D (pursuing)  \n\n

                • Sister Jincy A.C.  \n
                M.A., B.Ed  \n
                Social Movement in India  \n\n

                • Dr. Juhi Singh  \n
                M.A., Ph.D. , NET  \n\n

                 •Dr. Chinmayee Mohanty  \n
                PhD, M.Phil \n\n

                • Dr. Ragini Ranjan  \n
                M.A, B.Ed, Ph.D  \n
                Anthropology  \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts15">

                 •Our students have secured top positions in the merit list of Patna University. \n\n
                 •The Department has a well-equipped library to strengthen teaching, learning and research activities. \n\n
                 •The students of the Department have achieved success in various fields. They are working in different colleges, educational
            institutions, civil services, and banking sectors.  \n\n

        </string>

    <string name="arts15faculties">
                 •Dr. Smita Kumari(HOD) \n
                M.A, Ph.D  \n
                Sahitya \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="arts16">

             •The Department of Urdu, counted as one among the oldest departments in the College, has
            seen over the past years hundred of students pass through its portals with enriched knowledge. \n\n
             •The aim of the department is primarily to guide and counsel the individual students in the way best suited
            to them. The students have performed impressively well, year after year. \n\n
             •This is a department which imparts education and morals to the students. Students are fully motivated
            to achieve their ambitions. This department has the power to produce the desired growth in the personality of the students as well. \n\n
             •The department enhances the language skills and impart them lessons of creative writing skills. Urdu Department will definitely help
            in unveiling an undiscovered path to success.  \n\n
             •The Urdu Department where Education and Civilization smell together. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="arts16faculties">
        • Dr Abdul Basit Hamidi(HOD) \n
        Ph.D.(NET,JRF) \n \n
        </string>


    <!--        <string name="Sci1">-->
    <!--            1.COMPUTER APPLICATION \n-->
    <!--              1.1 MCA \n-->
    <!--                1.2 BCA \n\n-->
    <!--        </string>-->


    <string name="science1mca">
            • Wi-Fi connectivity and high-speed Internet leased line connection. \n\n
            • On-the-Job Training is done by students in various organizations. \n\n
            • Campus Placement for deserving Students. \n\n
            • Regular monitoring of students through Terminal tests, projects, e-learning Computer-based tutorials, Presentation through Laptop and Projector. \n\n
            • Faculty support to students. \n\n
            • Online Tutorial from IIT Mumbai is conducted for college students under the NMEICT project Talk -to -A Teacher.  \n\n
            • A rich departmental library, to enhance the teaching-learning process. \n\n
            • Add-on certificate course is conducted as per professional demand in IT Industry. \n\n
            • Tutorials and Remedial classes for students. \n\n
            • Top rank achieved by students in UniversityExaminations. \n\n
            • Counseling sessions for placement and on-the-job training. \n\n
            • Research Projects have taken by students under the CPE scheme. \n\n
            • Parent- Teacher meet. \n\n
        </string>

    <string name="science1mcafaculties">
                  •Dr. Bhawna Sinha(HOD)\n
                    Ph.D, M.Phil, MCA, MBA \n\n

                  •Ms. Sushmita Chakraborty\n
                    MCA,DBMS\n\n

                  •Mr.Praveen Kumar\n
                    M.Tech, MCA\n
                    Web Technology \n\n

                  • Mr. Braj Kishore Prasad \n
                    M.Tech,MCA\n
                    Network Security\n\n

                  • Ms Poonam A Lakra\n
                    MCA\n\n


                  • Dr. Priyadarshini \n
                    MCA, M.Sc, Ph.D. \n\n

                  • Ms. Pratima Kumari \n
                    B.Tech, M.Tech, UGC NET \n\n
        </string>


    <string name="science1bca">
            • Top positions achieved by students of the Department in University Examinations.\n\n
            • Regular monitoring of students through Terminal exams, projects, assignments, presentations etc.\n\n
            • Students undergo On-the -Job Training in various organizations. \n\n
            • Faculty support to the students. \n\n
            • Research Projects taken by students under CPE scheme. \n\n
            • The Department of Computer Science has been included as one of the Science Departments under the
            Star College Scheme granted by the Department of Biotechnology, Govt. of India. Under this scheme the department
            conducts various training programmes and Workshops for the students and teachers to enhance their knowledge base. \n\n
            • Online Tutorial from IIT Mumbai is conducted for college students under the NMEICT project Talk -to –a- Teacher.\n\n
            • Parent- Teacher meet.\n\n
            • A rich departmental library to enhance the teaching -learning process.\n\n
            • Three Add-on certificate courses are conducted to make the student computer literate, self sufficient and accomplished
            as per the requirement of the present time. \n\n
            • Campus Placement for students in companies like WIPRO, TCS etc.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="science1bcafaculties">
            • Ms. Manisha Prasad(HOD)\n
            MCA IT, NET \n\n

            • Ms. Anshu \n
            M.Sc. (IT)\n\n

            • Ms. Amrita Prakash \n
            MCA, M.Tech \n\n

            • Ms.Renu Kumari \n
            MCA IT \n\n

            • Ms. Nimisha Manan \n
            MCA IT \n\n

            • Ms. Deepa Sonal \n
            MCA, NET \n\n

            • Mr. Sudhir Kumar \n
            M.Sc Maths \n\n
        </string>


    <string name="science2">
            • Department of Biotechnology aims to provide holistic education by innovative
        teaching, extracurricular activities, seminars and workshops. \n\n
            • Well-equipped lab with advanced instrumentation facility. \n\n
            • Broad area of researches are Molecular biology, Plant biotechnology,
        Computational biology, Environmental biotechnology and nanobiotechnology
            • Strong emphasis on modern biotechnology skills and extensive laboratory training. \n\n
            • Inculcating Scientific attitude and skills in students through regular Hands-on-experiments. \n\n
            • Well framed curriculum and syllabi to meet the challenges of growing demands of Biotechnology
              Organization of skill development programs on regular basis for students. \n\n
            • Guest lectures on cutting-edge areas of Biotechnological research. \n\n
            • Regular interaction of students with industry personnel for wide exposure. \n\n
            • Continuous assessment of students through projects, assignments and presentations. \n\n
            • Involvement of students in extracurricular activities for holistic development of students.\n\n
            • Experienced faculty support to conquer scientific knowledge and excel. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science2faculties">
            • Teaching Staff \n
            • Dr. Arti Kumari (HOD) \n
            Biotechnology \n
            Ph.D, M.Sc, NET,GATE \n\n

            • Dr. Vivek Raj \n
            Ph.D,M.Sc,GATE \n
            Biotechnology \n\n

            • Dr. Nivedita Priyadarshni \n
            Biotechnology \n
            Ph.D, M.Sc\n\n

             • Dr. Alok Ranjan \n
            Ph.D, Molecular Biology \n\n

            • Dr. PREMLATA KUMARI \n
            Ph.D., M.Sc., GATE \n\n
    </string>


    <string name="science3">
               • Regular Seminars and Group Discussions are held to enhance communication skills. \n\n
               • Academic evaluation of students by Terminal Examinations.\n\n
               • Monitoring of the student’s experimental skills by assignments. \n\n
               • Exposure trips to Industries and Research institutions, places of Botanical Interests. \n\n
               • Well equipped laboratories with advanced facilities. \n\n
               • Active participation in co-curricular and extra curricular activities. \n\n
               • Undergraduate Research under college with potential for Excellence and Basic
        Scientific Research scheme of UGC. \n\n
               • Departmental library with the recent edition of books and journals for reference.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science3faculties">
               • Dr. Pinky Prasad (HOD) \n
                Ph.D \n
                Plant Pathology\n\n

               • Dr. Hena Naz \n
                M.Sc, Ph.D \n
                Cytogenetics \n\n

               • Dr. Piyush Kumar Rai \n
                Ph.D, M.Sc\n\n

                •Dr. Urvashi Sinha \n
                Ph.D, M.Sc \n\n

               • Dr. ANJANA VERMA \n
                BET, PhD, M.Sc. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science4">
       • Regular Seminars and Group Discussions are held to enhance communication skills.\n\n
       • Academic evaluation of students by Terminal Examinations. \n\n
        • Monitoring of the student’s experimental skills by assignments. \n\n
       • Exposure trips to Industries and Research institutions, places of Botanical Interests. \n\n
       • Well equipped laboratories with advanced facilities.\n\n
       • Active participation in co-curricular and extra curricular activities.\n\n
       • Undergraduate Research under college with potential for Excellence and Basic Scientific Research scheme of UGC.\n\n
       • Departmental library with a recent edition of books and journals for reference.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="science4faculties">
       • Dr.(Mrs) Madhu Rani Sinha(HOD) \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D, B.Ed \n
        Physical Chemistry \n\n

       • Dr. Ashish Kumar \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D \n
        Organic Chemistry \n\n

       • Dr. Jyotsna Kumari \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D, B.Ed \n
        Organic Chemistry \n\n

       • Dr. Jyoti Chandra \n
        Ph.D., M.Sc.,B.Sc.,NET-JRF \n\n

       • Dr. Nandini \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D \n
        Inorganic Chemistry \n\n

      • Rabindra Nath Roy Majumdar \n
        MSc., M.Ed Chemistry \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science5">
       • Students secured good ranks in Patna University. Six girls among the top ten in Patna University Examination. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science5faculties">
       • Dr. Seema Mishra \n
        M.Sc., Ph.D, Net \n
        Pure Mathematics \n\n

       • Dr. Julee Shahni \n
        M.Sc., Ph.D \n\n

       • Dr. Ravi Kumar \n
        M.Sc, (IITG) Ph. D \n
        Applied Mathematics\n\n

       • Ms. JAYA BHUSHAN \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D(pursuing) \n\n

       • Dr. Ajay Kumar \n
        B.Sc., M.Sc. and Ph.D. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science6">
           • Regular lectures by guest speakers on specialized topics.  \n\n
           • Hands-on training in Microbiology and Biochemical Techniques, Mushroom
        cultivation, Basic Tissue Culture Techniques and Statistical Analysis. \n\n
           • Regular Seminars and Group Discussions to enhance communication skills. \n\n
           • Academic Evaluation of students by Terminal Examinations.\n\n
           • Monitoring of the student’s Experimental skills by Assignments and Annual Projects.\n\n
           • Exposure trips to various Industries and Research Institutions.\n\n
           • Development of Computer literacy and Entrepreneurship skills. \n\n
           • Departmental library with the recent edition of Books  and Journal for students reference. \n\n
           • Well equipped laboratories with tissue culture and instrumentation facilities. \n\n
           • Active Participation in Cultural Programmes and Extra-Curricular activities. \n\n
           • Students going for higher studies in reputed institutions of India and abroad.\n\n
           • Regular Parent-Teacher interaction and feedback from the students. \n\n
           • Smart Boards are used for teaching and learning purpose. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science6faculties">
       • Dr. Jaya Philip(HOD) \n
        M.Sc, GATE, PhD, NET Qualified \n
        Microbiology \n\n

       • Dr. Arti Kumari \n
        M.Sc,GATE,PhD \n
        Biotechnology \n\n

       • Dr. Swetnisha \n
        M.Sc., CSIR-NET, PhD \n\n

       • Dr. Niti Yashvardhini \n
        M.Sc, GATE, Ph.D., NET \n\n

       • Dr. Preeti Swarupa \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D., NET \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science7">
       • Students secured 1st rank in the university from the beginning of the Honours course i.e 1988 batch. \n\n
       • A Comprehensive Report of NATIONAL SYMPOSIUM on “Ethics in Science and Technology” \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science7faculties">
           • Dr. Aprajita Krishna \n
            HOD, Physics \n
            M.Sc, Ph.D, Dean Faculty of Science , National, International and Consultancy \n\n

           • Dr. Kavita Verma \n
            M.Sc, Ph.D \n\n

           • Dr. Rohit Singh\n
            M.Sc, Ph.D \n\n

           • Dr. Amrita \n
            M.Sc, Ph.D \n\n

           • Ms. Riekshika Sanwari \n
            M.Sc. , Ph.D \n\n

          •  DHARMENDRA RAI \n
            M.Sc, UGC NET \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science8">
           • Experienced faculties of the Department are devoted to excellence in their
        respective areas of specialization. \n\n
           • Extra care is taken to pay individual attention to the students in their practical work and tutorial sessions.\n\n
           • Project work and problem sessions are encouraged to develop innovation and analytical
        approach to Statistical learning.\n\n
          • The department is devoted student’s research work under the CPE and BSR (Project work) scheme. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science8faculties">
            • Ms. Moon(HOD)\n
            M.Sc., B.Ed \n
            Demography \n\n

           • Dr. Vikash Kumar \n
            PhD \n\n

           • Dr. Amit Kumar \n
            PhD, NET \n\n
    </string>


    <string name="science9">
           • Students secure good ranks in Patna University. 6-9 girls are among the top ten in Patna University Exams.  \n\n
           • Organizes students activities on a regular basis under the banner of Environment Conservation
        Outreach (ECO) task force. \n\n
           • Completed one UGC Major Project and two Minor Projects. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="science9faculties">
       • Dr. Shobha Srivastava (HOD)\n
        M.Sc, Ph.D \n
        Entomology \n\n

       • Dr. Sister Stuti A.C.\n
        M.Sc, Ph.D. Entomology and Vermitechnology \n\n

       • Mr. Sumeet Ranjan \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D \n\n

       • Dr. Anupma Kumari \n
        B.Sc, M. Sc., Ph.D \n\n


       • Dr. Neetu \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D \n\n

       • Mr. RAJEEV RANJANn \n
        M. Sc., NET-JRF, GATE \n\n

       • Dr. Sapna Kumari \n
        M.Sc, Ph. D, CSIR- NET \n\n

       • Dr. Kumari Sugandha Priya \n
        M.Sc, Ph.D \n\n

       • Dr. Aprajita Singh \n
        M.Sc. , Ph.D \n\n
    </string>


    <string name="commerce1">
    • 100% result with good percentage and every year 8 to 9 students come under the
        top 10 rank holders at the university level.\n\n
    • Teaching through visual aids.\n\n
    • Special care for weak students.\n\n
    • Corporate experience through on the job training for IInd year students.\n\n
    • Industrial exposure to IIIrd year students to the Industries like : Geetanjali, Mother Dairy, Parle-G etc.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="commerce1faculties">
        • Dr.Pallawi Ambreesh Kumar. (HOD) \n
        M.B.A, Ph.D, NET \n
        HRM\n\n

        • Ms. Satnam Kaur\n
        BBA, MBA, UGC-NET\n\n

        • Ms. Kumari Priya\n
        Ph.D, NET, M.B.A, ARPITA\n\n

        • Dr. RUCHITA MASIH\n
        MBA, Ph.D in Management, UGC NET\n\n

        • Dr. Kumari Soni\n
        Ph.D, M.B.A, BBA\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="commerce2">
    • Establishment of Commerce Lab to provide students knowledge in five specialized sections
     viz:-  Banking, Accountancy, Insurance, Foreign Exchange and Stock Exchange.\n\n
    • Internship arranged for many students in the companies like Kotak Securities, Lohia
     Securities Pvt. Ltd. and Fast Capital Markets Ltd.\n\n
    • Seminars, Group Discussions are conducted regularly.\n\n
    • Special guidelines and motivation for career orientation to students.\n\n
    • Spotlight on current economic and business scenario.\n\n
    • Modern means of teaching like PowerPoint Presentation in the class.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="commerce2faculties">
        • Dr. Soofia Fatima(HOD)\n
        M.Com, Ph.D\n
        Accounts\n\n

        • Ms. Kirti Kamal\n
        M.Com, B.Com\n\n

        • Mr. Gautam Saurabh\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET\n\n

        • Ms. Nikki Tiwari\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET\n\n

        • Ms. PUJA KUMARI\n
        M.Com, B.Com\n\n

        • Ms. Shweta Shah\n
        C.S., C.A (Final)\n
        Taxation\n\n

        • Ms. Sagarika\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET\n\n

        • Ms.Neha Raj Gupta\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET\n\n

        • Anup Sharma\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET,HRM\n\n

        • Ms. SOHINI PRIYA\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET,Ph.D. Pursuing\n\n

        • Mona Kumari\n
        M.Com, UGC-NET,HRM\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="commerce3">
    • The Department has an impressive track record in terms of the Alumni being placed in diffrent
        frontline organizations like ICICI Bank, Ranbaxy, HDFC Bank, Hindustan Times, Bajaj Capital, LIC etc.\n\n
    • In the final year, the department arranges for regular visits to Blue Chip Companies
        like Godrej,Whirlpool, Maruti Udyog Ltd, UB Group,Sudha, Pepsi,Bisleri,HMT(Tractors)etc.
        in order to provide an exlellent corporate exposure.The students are made to learn the
        professional skills through on the job-Training in the sixth semester in diffrent sectors
        like Banking, Telecom Industry, Hospitality, Media etc\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="commerce3faculties">
        • Dr. Shazia Rahman (HOD)\n
        M.A, MBA, PhD\n\n

        • Ms. Nusrath Sohail\n
        MBA (HR)\n\n

        • Dr. Dharmendra Kumar Singh\n
        MBA, NET (UGC),Ph.D\n\n

        • Alok John\n
        Ph.D. (pursuing), UGC – NET, MBA, PGDM.\n\n

        • Ms.Yosha Singh\n
        M.B.A\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="BEd">
        • In view of the high demand for teacher training programmes in the sta Patna Women’s College
          applied to National Council for Teacher Education (NCTE) in 2005 to introduce B.Ed.and to start the Department of Education on its premises.\n\n
        • NCTE granted recognition to the Department on 21 June 2005. \n\n
        • The College officially introduced and inaugurated the BES programme and the Department of Education on 8 April, 2006. \n\n
        • The Department was accredited with an ‘A’ grade by NAAC with CGPA 3.52 out4 in 2011. \n\n
        • The B.Ed. programme of the Department is of two academic years (four semesters) duration. \n\n
        • At present, the Department runs the programme for two units (100 students). \n\n
        • The Department does its best to provide comprehensive educational experiences to prospective teachers in consonance with its objectives. \n\n
        • It organizes a number of workshops, seminars, guest lectures, orientation and personality development programmes regularly. \n\n
        • Value education and Theology classes are part of the curriculum to inculcate moral and ethical values and to inspire an honest and conscientious worldview. \n\n
        • To encourage ‘we-feeling and to promote a sense of belongingness to the surrounding community, the prospective teachers are encouraged to
        participate in several campus-to-community programmes. \n\n
        • The Department also organizes National and State level Workshops/Conferences/Seminars for skill development and research orientation
        of the teaching community and students from time to time. \n\n
        • ICT resource centres such as Smart Class, Multimedia Room, e-library and Computer Lab with free broadband Internet facility are
        provided to strengthen 21st-century skills and to provide diverse and comprehensive learning experiences to prospective teachers. \n\n
        • Recently the campus has acquired Wifi. \n\n
        • The students of the Department have performed remarkably well in the Patna University Examinations over the years. \n\n
        • They have been placed in renowned schools in Bihar and of other states through campus and non-campus selection procedures.  \n\n
        • Some of them have pursued higher education and won laurels for their accomplishments. \n\n
        • The Department helps prospective teachers to discover their latent capabilities and develop them into skilled and alert
        learners who are able to lead a fine teaching career. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="BEdFaculties">
           • Sister (Dr.)M. Saroj A.C(HOD) \n
             B.Ed., M.Ed \n\n

            • Ms. Waeza Afshan\n
            M.A.(Eng), M.Ed., NET \n\n

           • Swati Shilpi \n
            MA, M.Ed. NET \n\n

           • Dr Shubhra \n
            BSc-BCA, M.Ed, MA (Psy), PhD \n\n

           • Ritika Shree \n
            MSc(Math), MEd, UGC NET, \n\n

           • Dr Prabhas Ranjan \n
            MA (His), MA (Soc), B.Ed., M.Ed, PhD \n\n

           • Dr Nitu Chauhan \n
            MA (Hindi), MEd, PhD \n\n

           • Dr. Neena Verma \n
            MA, MEd, PhD \n\n

           • Mona Kumari \n
            M.A.(Eco), M.Ed., NET \n\n

           • Dr. Madhumita \n
            B.Ed., M.Ed, Ph.D. \n\n

           • Fr John Britto \n
            B.Ed., M.Ed., M.Sc. Chemistry\n\n

           • Ms. Quazi Bushra Ahmed \n
            B.P.Ed., M.P.Ed \n\n

           • Yamini \n
            MA(Sociology), MA(Kathak Dance) \n\n

           • Dr.Sister Jincy A.C. \n
            MA, PhD/p> \n\n

           • Ms. Geetanjali Choudhary \n
            PGDFD,M.A., MFA \n\n

            • Dr. Rashmi Sinha \n
            B.Ed., M.Ed. PhD \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="names">
        SWETA KUMARI
    </string>

    <string name="subHeading">
         Autonomous\n
        Patna University\n
        3rd Cycle NAAC Accredited at \'A\' grade \n with CGPA 3.58/4\n
    </string>

</resources>